Guide to the Council on Southeast Asia Studies, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Subject files, 1942-1972; Series II
  - Writings and Lectures
    - Departmental Files
      - Council on Southeast Asia Studies
        - correspondence, 1952-1963 (Box 24, Folder 462)
        - correspondence, 1964-1971, undated (Box 24, Folder 463)
        - agendas, minutes of meetings, and memoranda, 1961-1968, undated (Box 24, Folder 464)
      - Yale University Graduate School Bulletin, 1968-1969 (Box 25, Folder 465)
      - Yale University History Department
        - correspondence, 1962-1966 (Box 25, Folder 466)
        - correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 25, Folder 467)
      - Indonesia Handbook,H.E.W. grant, edited by Ruth McVey
        - correspondence, 1960-1970 (Box 25, Folder 468)
      - Yale University Department of Political Science
        - correspondence, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 469)
      - Yale University History Department
        - examinations, 1959-1965, undated (Box 25, Folder 470)
        - examinations, 1966-1971, undated (Box 25, Folder 471)
        - grade sheets, 1966-1971 (Box 25, Folder 472)
        - information for graduate students, 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 473)
      - Recommendations for employment, 1967-1970 (Box 25, Folder 474)
      - Yale Southeast Asia Discussion Group
        - correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 25, Folder 475)
        - correspondence, 1965-1968, undated (Box 25, Folder 476)
      - Southeast Asia Studies Center, relocations of the department, 1967-1971 (Box 25, Folder 477)
      - Southeast Asia Studies Library correspondence
        - 1948-1954 (Box 25, Folder 478)
        - 1955-1960 (Box 25, Folder 479)
        - 1961 (Box 25, Folder 480)
        - 1962 (Box 25, Folder 481)
        - 1963 (Box 26, Folder 482)
          Material is closed to reseachers until January 1, 2046 due to University policy.
        - 1964-1965 (Box 26, Folder 483)
          The material is closed until January 1, 2046 due to University policy.
        - 1966-1969 (Box 26, Folder 484)
        - 1970-1971, no date (Box 26, Folder 485)
      - Speaking engagements on Vietnam and Southeast Asia
        - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 486)
        - correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 26, Folder 487)
        - correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 26, Folder 488)
      - Student inquiries about Southeast Asia Graduate Program
        - correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 26, Folder 489)
      - Yale University Press
        - correspondence, 1961-1970 (Box 26, Folder 490)
      - Requests for payment of temporary employees, 1963-1966 (Box 26)
      - Source statements, 1965-1967 (Box 26)
      - Statements of accounts, bills, memoranda, 1964-1966 (Box 26)
      - Southeast Asia Studies, Faculty and Student lists, 1969-1970 (Box 26, Folder 491)
      - A General, 1956-1971 (Box 26, Folder 493)
      - B General, 1959-1970 (Box 26, Folder 495)
      - C General, 1957-1971 (Box 27, Folder 496)
      - D General, 1957-1968 (Box 27, Folder 497)
      - F General, 1957-1970 (Box 27, Folder 498)
      - G General, 1958-1966 (Box 27, Folder 500)
      - H General, 1957-1971 (Box 27, Folder 501)
      - J General, 1958-1963 (Box 27, Folder 502)
      - K General, 1956-1971 (Box 27, Folder 503)
      - L General, 1956-1970 (Box 27, Folder 505)
      - M General, 1958-1969 (Box 27, Folder 506)
      - M General, 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 507)
      - N General, 1958-1971 (Box 27, Folder 508)
      - O General, 1960-1961 (Box 27, Folder 511)
      - P General, 1960-1961 (Box 28, Folder 513)
      - Q General, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 514)
      - R General, 1959-1970 (Box 28, Folder 516)
      - S General, 1959-1971 (Box 28, Folder 518)
      - T General, 1959-1971 (Box 28, Folder 524)
      - X, Y, Z General, 1968-1970 (Box 28, Folder 530)
      - Departmental publication files (Box 29–35)
- Records of the Council on Southeast Asian Studies, circa 1951-1970; Accession 19ND-A-087
  Student files and student inquiries are restricted until January 1, 2026 as established by Yale Corporation regulations..
  - Administrative files
    - Honorary degree nomination: Ambassador Soedjatmoko (Box 1)
    - Lectures, 1951-1969 (Box 1)
    - Visitors, 1960-1970 (Box 1)
    - Lecturers and visitors
      - Thai dancers, 1962 (Box 1)
      - Japanese soiree, 1964 (Box 1)
      - Lansdale, Edward G., 1964 (Box 1)
    - Library
      - Conferences, 1953, 1955, 1958 (Box 1)
      - Organization (Box 1)
    - Religious Studies, Dept, of, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Student information sheets, 1960s (Box 1)
  - Publication files
    - Indonesian handbook (Box 2)
    - Translation of "Japanese military administration in Indonesia" (Box 2)
    - Articles, reports and notes on Micronesia, by or for Dr. John Embree
      - E--(m--8), 1945-1946 (Box 5)
      - E--(n--8), 1944-1947 (Box 5)
      - E--(o--1), 1946 (Box 5)
      - E--(p--3), 1932-1946 (Box 5)
      - E--(q--6), 1946 (Box 5)
      - E--(r--1), 1945-1946 (Box 5)
      - E--(s--5), 1940-1945 (Box 5)
      - E--(t--18), 1943-1949 (Box 5)
      - E--u--1-photographs, 1940s (Box 5)
    - A Report on the U.S. Navy Military Government of Marshall Islands, Confidential, 1944-1945 (Box 5)
    - Strategic Bulletins, Oceania, No. 1: Gazeteer of the Marshall Islands, compiled by Cross-Cultural Survey, Institute of Human Relations, Yale University, 1943 January 2 (Box 5)
    - Field Report on Trip to Micronesia, December 14, 1945 to January 5, 1946, by John F. Embree (Box 5)
    - Military Government in Saipan and Tinian, by John F. Embree, 1945 September 12 (Box 5)
    - Observations at the Military Government Camps for Civilians on Saipan and Tinian in August 1945 (Box 5)
    - April, 1944 Inspection of Certain Marshall Island Atolls, Unit No. 1: South Sector Atolls (Box 5)
    - Notes on Truk, by Ned Hall, 1946 (Box 5)
    - Observations of Military Government Operations, Pacific Areas, by Malcolm S. MacLean, 1945 May 1 (Box 5)
    - Palau: Notes, by John Useem, Circa 1946 (Box 5)
  - Student files
    Student files are restricted until January 1, 2026 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - SEAS Student Inquiries, 1954-1966 (Box 4)
    Student inquiries are restricted until January 1, 2026 due to University policy set by the Yale Corporation.